Tonight we had decided to talk about Creation but our management has not been able to provide
今晚我們決定談論創造，但我們的管理層無法提供
me with a chalk and with a blackboard so, I don’t know, I’ll try to explain it without
粉筆和黑板，所以，我不知道，我會嘗試
drawing.
不用圖來解釋。
It’s a very difficult subject.
這是一個非常艱深的主題。
And I’ll try to make it intelligible.
我會嘗試讓它變得易懂。
But I would request you to pay full attention for such a difficult subject like Creation.
我請求你們對這樣一個艱深的主題，如創造，給予充分的注意力。
The greatest blessing today is that many of you can feel the vibrations.
現代最大的祝福是你們中有許多人能夠感受到這些生命能量。
And not only that but you also know and realise that they can think and they can love.
不僅如此，你們知道並意識到生命能量能夠思考和去愛。
It’s a very big blessing.
這是一個非常大的祝福。
Of course, some of you haven’t got it, but those who have got it know that these vibrations
當然，有些人還沒感受到，但那些已經感受過的人知道這些生命能量
organise, because they raise the Kundalini, they go to the place where it is needed, out
是有組織的，因為它們提升了昆達里尼，到有需要的地方，出於
of compassion, to that portion where there is deficiency.
大愛，去到不足的那部分。
They understand, they organise they are universal in nature and they love.
它們理解，它們組織，它們本質上是廣布的，是愛。
They answer to your questions, when you ask them some questions – you receive answer
當你向它們提出問題時，它們會回答你的問題——你會收到答案。
from them.
來自生命能量。
They are living vibrations.
生命能量是活的。
These vibrations are from the Divine.
這些生命能量來自於神聖。
This Divine is called as Brahma, Brahma Tattwa, Principle of Divine.
這神聖被稱為梵，梵的本質，是神聖的原則。
We can say that the process of Creation is an eternal process.
我們可以說創造的過程是一個永恆的過程。
Means a seed becomes a tree and the tree becomes a seed, and the seed becomes a tree, and it
意思是一顆種子變成樹，樹變成種子，然後種子又變成樹，這樣不斷循環。
goes on and on – it’s eternal.
這樣持續下去——這是永恆的。
So, it cannot have a starting point and it cannot have an ending point.
所以，它沒有起點，也沒有終點。
It goes on and on and on.
它不斷地延續下去。
That’s why it can have different states of existence, you can say, state of being.
這就是為什麼它可以有不同的存在狀態，你可以說是存有的狀態。
So, the first, just the being, is Brahma, where nothing exists.
最開始當一切不存在時，首先存在的就是梵。
We say ‘nothing’.
我們說「不存在」。
When we say nothing, it is a relative word: because we do not exist, so we say ‘nothing
當我們說不存在時，這是一個相對的用詞：因為我們自己不存在，所以我們說「甚麼都不存在」。
exists’ – it’s a relative word.
存在是相對的詞。
When we are not existing, for us everything is ‘nothing’.
當我們不存在時，對我們來說一切都是「無」。
There is something, but that is not ourselves.
有某些東西確實存在，但不是我們自己。
And that’s why, relatively, we say it is ‘nothing’.
這就是為什麼，我們相對地說它是「無」。
It’s only the word Brahma, we can say.
我們可以說這就是「梵」這個詞。
You can think of an energy, if you want to, an energy-form that exists.
如果你願意，你可以把它想成一種存在的能量，能量的形式。
But the energy accumulates at a point and forms a nucleus.
能量在一個點上積累,因而形成一個核心。
The energy that thinks, energy that is distributed, accumulates at a point, concentrates on a
會思考的能量，會散佈的能量，積累在一個點上，集中在一個
point, you can say, and this point is the point we call as Sadashiva.
點上，你可以說，這個點就是我們所稱的全能主。
This happens because that energy desires, thinks, organises, loves.
這個發生是因為那能量有渴望、會思考、組織、愛。
When it wants to create, when the desire is felt in that energy to create, at that time
當祂想要創造，當能量感受到創造的渴望，這時
a nucleus is created.
一個核心被創造出來。
This nucleus we call as Sadashiva.
我們稱這個核心為全能主。
This nucleus does not disappear.
這個核心不會消失。
You can think of a nebula.
你可以想像一個星雲。
I mean, it is something which is all relative you can think, you cannot think something
我的意思是，你可以用相對的概念來想，但你無法以絕對的形式
in absolute form.
來思考某件事。
So, with thinking you cannot conceptualise the whole thing, but if you can think of a
因此，你無法經由思考來將整件事物概念化，假設你能夠思考
state, where it’s just an energy and no creation.
一種狀態，只是一個能量，但沒有創造。
But not the energy of electricity, magnetism – all these things.
不是電力、磁力等所有這些東西的能量。
Is the combination, the synthesis of all the things which goes into laya which becomes
而是所有事物結合、融合，最終化為「拉亞」（laya），
that, dissolves into that.
最後又消融於此。
It coagulates on a point, that may be a [suitable] word, coagulates at a point which we can call
它在一個點凝聚，或許用一個適當的字眼來形容，凝聚於一點，我們可以稱之為
as a nucleus.
核心。
This point we call as Sadashiva.
我們稱這一個核心點為全能主。
This Sadashiva is the Ishwara, is the God Almighty.
這個全能主就是上主，是全能的神。
We call it now “God” because now it has a limitation.
我們現在稱祂為「上帝」，因為語言文字有其限制。
In the sense that we can call it something.
從某種意義上說，我們可以稱某為某種東西。
But if it is just an energy we just call it a Brahma.
但如果它只是一種能量，我們就稱之為梵。
You can say like this: when the water becomes ice, a follicle of ice is formed, you can
你可以這樣說：當水變成冰時，形成了一個冰的顆粒，你可以
differentiate between the water and the ice, but still, it’s a relative, relative understanding.
區分水和冰，但這仍然是一種相對性、相對性的理解。
At this state God Almighty, Parameshwara, takes its form as an identity.
在這個狀態下，全能上帝，最高神，以一種可辨識的身份顯現。
That’s why we can say that it is not Brahma, but an identity.
這就是為什麼我們可以說祂不是梵，而是一個身份。
Identity has its aura, has its aura, we can say, its light.
這身份有其光環，這光環，我們可以說，光。
This light is the Divine Love.
這光就是神聖的愛。
It goes into various forms but Sadashiva remains as He is.
祂以各種形式存在，但全能主維持不變。
Now, the desire to create is transferred to the aura.
然後，創造的渴望轉移到了光環上。
The aura is the Power of God, Shakti.
光環是上帝的力量，Shakti。
Ishwara has certain things beyond Him also and before Him.
上主有某些事物是超越祂自身，也有在祂之前。
God Almighty has something beyond Him that He cannot control: one, He cannot control
全能的上帝有一些他無法控制的事物：一個，他無法控制
His eternal nature.
就是祂永恆的本性。
It is His nature to be eternal, He cannot stop it.
祂的本性就是永恆，祂無法停止。
He will go on changing His form, it is His nature, it just… it is His swabhava.
祂會不斷改變祂的形態，這是祂的本性，這就是…這是祂的自性。
He cannot change it, His eternal nature.
祂無法改變，祂永恆的本性。
He will be eternally.
祂將永遠存在。
Eternity is His temperament, His nature, He cannot overcome that.
永恆是祂的脾性，祂的本性，祂無法克服這一點。
For example, God cannot take away your freedom to choose the Truth.
例如，上帝無法剝奪你有選擇真理的自由。
He cannot.
祂不能。
Once He has granted, He’s not going to take it away.
一旦祂賜予，祂不會收回。
You have to choose it in all your freedom.
你必須在完全自由的情況下選擇祂。
He will not force you to take it.
祂不會強迫你去接受。
Many people have hopes like that – they are sadly mistaken.
許多人有這樣的希望——他們可悲地錯了。
At this juncture only lies the problem of complete destruction or complete resurrection.
在這個時刻，問題在於完全毀滅 或完全重生。
It is left into the hands of human beings to decide whether they want to accept the
人類要取決 他們是否願意接受這一點。
Truth or if they want to follow the falsehood.
真理 或他們願意追隨假象。
So, you have [been] given complete freedom to choose.
你被賦予了完全的選擇自由。
I won’t go into the details about God Almighty, because it’s a very subtler subject and
我不會詳細討論全能的上帝，因為這是一個非常精微的主題，
requires much more attention.
需要更強的注意力。
I have talked about it before to many people and all His nature, they know that.
我之前已經和很多人談過這件事，他們都知道祂的本性。
But He is the Witness, He is the Sakshi (witness) in the form of a Sakshi.
祂是見證者，祂以見證者的形式存在。
What is He witnessing?
祂在見證什麼？
He is witnessing the Creation.
他在見證 創造。
And the power that creates the Creation is the Shakti, is His power, is His consort.
創造的力量是 Shakti，是祂的力量，是祂的伴侶。
Now, for us, human beings, we don’t understand that a wife and a husband could be that one
現在，對於我們人類來說，我們無法明白妻子和丈夫可以是完全（合一）。
(unified).
一體。
For example, you can understand like a Sun and a sunlight, Moon and the Moonlight – as
例如，你可以理解太陽和陽光，月亮和月光——比喻
these two things are one and the same.
這兩樣是一體的。
Or the meaning and the word.
或者說 詞語和意義。
In the same way, Shiva and Shakti are one together.
以同樣的方式，全能上帝和祂的Shakti(力量)是一體的。
For example, you can be a father, you can be a mother.
例如，你可以是父親，你可以是母親。
You can be a father, you can be a brother, you can be a son – three things you are
你可以是父親，也是兄弟，也是兒子——你可同時擁有三種身份。
doing together.
三個身分是一體的。
In the same way, you can be your Self and your power.
同樣的方式，你是自己(真我)也是你的力量。
You know: you and your Self and your power are different, but you are one.
你知道：你自己(真我)以及你的力量是不同的，但你們是一體的。
You have a power to write, but you are not your power.
你有寫作的能力，但你不是你的能力。
Neither your power is your Self.
你的力量也不是你。
In the same way, Shiva and Shakti are two persons to be identified, but they are part
同樣的方式，全能上帝和Shakti(力量)是兩個身分，但他們都是被稱為「梵」的一部分
and parcel of one uniform thing known as ‘Brahma’.
以及一個整體。
But these horrible Tantrikas – again they come round here – have spoiled the relationship
但這些可怕的密宗——他們到這—— 把這關係破壞掉
between Shiva and Shakti.
在上帝與Shakti(祂的力量)之間。
Not that they were human beings, that’s why they established all these funny ideas
因為這些人類，他們有這些奇怪的想法
and talked about these nonsensical things.
並談論這些荒謬的事情。
Because they are the people who are nothing but their sex-points.
因為這些人只認識他們自己的性點。
They are nothing nobler than that.
他們沒有更高尚的存在。
They are very depraved and diseased and debased people.
他們是非常墮落、病態和低賤的人類。
They suffer from such a terrible disease that no way they can see anything else but this.
他們遭受著如此可怕的疾病，以至於他們無法看到其他任何東西。
Ashvameda has also described as something to do with sex.
吠陀宗教所遵循的馬祭儀式也被描述為與性有關的事物。
Everything they look, they see sex there.
他們所看得到一切，都是性。
It’s like a person, as we call it in Hindi – [HINDI 13:00 mins] – who is wearing
這就像一個人，我們在印地語中稱之為 – [印地語 13:00 分鐘] – 戴著
the glass of sex and watching through that life, everything becomes sex, sex, sex, they
性的眼鏡，透過那個觀看生活，一切都變成了性、性、性，他們
are such debased and horrible depraved people, even God, they are bringing to that level.
是如此墮落和可怕的敗類，甚至連上帝，他們也帶到那個層次。
Unless and until they are bringing to that level, they cannot exist.
除非他們降到那個水準，他們無法存在。
How will they justify themselves, the way they are?
他們要如何為自己的所作所為辯解？
Sex has nothing to do with Shiva and Shakti.
性與上帝和Shakti(祂的力量)完全無關。
What is Sun and sunlight?
什麼是太陽和陽光？
Is there any sex involved there?
有涉及性嗎？
Is there nothing existing without sex for these horrible tantrikas?
這些可怕的密宗 難道沒有任何東西是存在於性之外的嗎？
Is there no relationship that exists without sex?
沒有任何關係可以無性存在嗎？
So, Shiva is the God Almighty – we should call him as Sadashiva.
所以，上帝是全能神 – 我們應該稱祂為全能主。
I’ll try to draw a little bit, let us see how it works out.
我會試著畫，讓我們看 創造是如何運作的。
Now forming into a nucleus like this.
開始 形成像這樣的一個核心。
Now, this is the remains of the nucleus, you can say, which forms its power here into a
然後 這是核心的殘餘，可以說，在這裡形成了祂的力量。
valaya.
進入盤繞的環。
How does it form?
它是如何形成的？
He moves supposing backwards, you can say.
他向後移動，可以這麼說。
Then what happens when he moves backwards…kara noko (marathi: don’t do that)…this, whole
那麼當他向後移動時會發生什麼…kara noko（馬拉地語：不要這樣做）…這，整個
thing like this, remains here and all of this passes, forms a shell around it and the waves
物體，留在這裡，所有這些都超越過去，在它周圍形成一個貝殼狀，然後波浪
cross over and settle onto the shell – here.
超越過然後落在殼上——這裡。
Now, this is the situation: when all inside forms another nucleus here by concentration
現在的情況：當裡面的一切通過集中形成另一個核心在這裡
– this is the Shakti.
– 這是Shakti(神力)。
And this is the Sadashiva.
這是全能主。
This is the Mahashakti, you can say ‘Adi Shakti’ and this is the Sadashiva.
這是摩訶迦利，你可以說「太初之母」，這是全能主。
Now here, Shiva, once the Shakti forms Her personality, or we can say, Her ego is established,
現在，上帝，一旦神力發展出她的個性，或者我們可以說，她的自我建立起來，
She is a different identity from Shiva.
她便擁有與上帝不同的身分。
Because the whole process is to create the play for the witness to see.
因為整個過程是為了創造一場讓"至高觀者"觀看的戲劇。
He is the One who is going to watch the play.
全能上帝是要觀看這場戲的那一位。
She is the One who is going to create it.
神力是要創造的那一位。
So, She accumulates Her ego onto a point here and becomes Shakti, assumes a position there.
所以，她在這裡累積她的自我，並成為神力，並在那裡擔任一個角色。
And the first thing She does as a Shakti is to go round in a parabolic…in a parabola
神力所要做的第一件事就是圍繞著她的主以拋物線的方式…
around Her Lord.
圍繞著她的主。
This point one must understand.
這一點大家必須理解。
She is a Shakti, is the Power of God.
她是神力，是上帝的力量。
And the whole Creation is only meant for God Almighty to be seen.
整個創造是為了讓全能的上帝觀看。
He’s the only spectator of the play of Shakti.
祂是神力戲劇的唯一觀者。
And if He doesn’t like the play, for example, He doesn’t like the way it is or the way
如果祂不喜歡現在的樣子，或不喜歡人們被創造出來的樣子、
people are that are created, He can immediately stop the play by closing His eyes, by denying
祂可以立即閉上眼睛、這齣戲就停了，
the play, by showing His annoyance or by His stopper, He can just stop it.
經由否認這齣戲，顯示祂的不悅，或經由祂的停止器，他可以直接停止這齣戲。
That’s why He is also called as a destroyer.
所以祂也被稱為毀滅者。
But the whole thing is meant for His amusement.
但整個創造是為了取悅祂。
And if it doesn’t give Him pleasure, He can stop it.
如果這創造讓祂感到不愉悅，祂可以停止它。
That’s why the first one who must be pleased is the One who is the spectator.
這就是為什麼第一個必須取悅的就是那位全能觀者。
Because of this, Shiva is garlanded by Her, is a parabola and that’s why parabola is
正因為如此，全能上帝被神力的花環所環繞，是一個拋物線，這就是為什麼拋物線是
the symbol of Adi Shakti.
太初之母的象徵。
This is sort of a certificate to Her, a sort of a granting Her the varadan, as we call
這對她來說是一種證書，算是一種授予她的恩惠，正如我們在梵語中所稱的
it in Sanskrit language, is the varadan that ‘go ahead with your work.’
在梵語中，這恩惠，意思是「繼續你的工作」。
This is a sanction given to Him.
這是給予祂的認可。
When She completes this parabola, the sanction has been granted and that’s why She is a
當她完成這個拋物線時，認證已經被授予，這就是為什麼她是一個
parabola.
拋物線。
Here the question of men dominating the women and women dominating the men does not come
在這裡，男性主導女性和女性主導男性的問題並不存在。
in, because this is predominantly in our heads, you see.
因為這主要存在於我們的頭腦中。
When we think of it, we think of men and women, it is nothing of the kind.
當我們想到這一點時，我們想到的是男性和女性，但事實並非如此。
It’s just complete Oneness.
這裡是完全的合一。
Can we think of one couple which is absolutely united with each other?
我們能否想到一對彼此完全合一的夫妻嗎？
We cannot.
我們不能。
Because we are all incomplete people.
因為我們都是不完整的人。
But if you could stretch your imagination to such a point that both of them are meant
如果你能發揮你的想像力，祂們兩個的存在只為彼此
for each other only and the One who is active, is the Adi Shakti, is only active to please
活躍的那一位，即太初之母，是為了取悅全能上帝而活躍，
the God Almighty Who is the only spectator of Her play and He’s to be pleased first.
祂是她戲劇唯一的觀眾，祂首先要感到愉悅。
So, She surrenders Herself before Him, takes the sanction through the parabola.
她在祂面前臣服，，透過拋物線法令。
Now, parabola is a very important thing.
拋物線非常重要。
You know that everything travels through parabola, never in a straight line.
一切都是通過拋物線運行的，不是直線。
For example, if you love someone, our love goes round that person and comes back to us
例如，如果你愛上某人，我們的愛會圍繞那個人，然後以愛的形式
as love.
回到我們身邊。
But if you hate that person, then our hatred goes round that person and comes back to us
但如果你恨某人，那麼我們的仇恨會圍繞那個人，然後以一種可怕的仇恨的形式
So, the parabola is taken, but you might say ‘why a parabola?’
所以，拋物線被採用，你可能會問「為什麼是拋物線？」
The question can be: “Why should there be a parabola and not a circle?”
問題可以是：「為什麼用拋物線而不是圓？」
The reason is: parabola is the shortest distance to go round another point, is the shortest.
原因是：通過拋物線最短的距離來繞過另一點、是最短的。
And that’s why it’s a parabola.
這就是為什麼要用拋物線。
It is even in our ordinary life, you will find this happening: that whatever you do
即使在我們日常生活中，你會發現這種狀況：你對他人所做的一切，
to others, it comes back to you in some form, whether you do good or bad.
無論是好是壞，它都會以某種形式回到你身上。
And that’s why our karmic ideas and that of our doing punyas are all there.
這就是為什麼有關我們業力和善有善報觀念存在的原因。
Because whatever we emit through us, will come back to us.
因為無論透過我們發出的任何東西，都會回到我們身上。
In the same way, if you bless the whole world, the blessings of the whole world will come
同樣的，如果你祝福全世界，全世界的祝福也會降臨
to us.
在我們身上。
As I told you, the process is not that simple as it can be drawn, because it’s a living
正如我說的，這個過程並不是像畫的那麼簡單，因為這是一個大層面的活生生的過程
process of a big dimension but I’m just trying to make it simpler for you to understand.
但我只是想讓你更容易理解。
Now, this parabola, when, here now, when She is, She goes into the motion of a parabola
現在，這個拋物線，當她進入拋物線的運動時
and Shiva sanctioned Her, sanctions Her – it’s a living process, again you must understand,
全能上帝也認可了，准許了她 —— 這是一個活的過程，你必須理解，
it’s a living process, it’s as human as we are.
這是一個活的過程，它和我們一樣人性化。
Both of them are as human as we are, we should say, they are thousand times more human than
祂們兩個和我們一樣人性化，我們應該說，他們比我們更人性化千倍。
we are.
他們比我們更人性化千倍
So, here the Wife, His Consort, says that: “I am very happy just like this.
所以，這個妻子，祂的伴侶，說：“我這樣就非常快樂。”
I won’t go any further with it."
我不會再繼續下去了。"
Because Creation is not an easy thing for Her, She doesn’t want to depart from Her
因為創造對她來說並不是一件容易的事，所以她不想離開她的
Creation.
創造。
Creation is the child and She says, “I would not like to have children now, because I will
創造是孩子，她說：“我現在不想要孩子，因為我會
lose you."
失去你。”
So, She pushes Herself towards Him and He pushes Her back and disappears, opening out
所以，她向祂推進，而祂又把她推回去，然後消失，從這裡
from here.
向外開放。
Now She is in this form.
現在她以這種形式存在。
So, the beginning of the Om starts.
這就是太初生命的起源。
Parabola, first of all, gets converted into Om.
拋物線，首先，轉化為太初生命。
Then She pushes Herself down and settles down for a while to meditate and to find out how
然後她把自己壓下來，靜下來冥想一會兒，看看她將如何
She is going to work it out, we can say like this.
繼續創造，我們可以這麼說。
You see, it is Her desire which must be aroused.
因為首先她創造的慾望必須被喚醒。
If Her desire is not aroused, She will not conceive the Creation.
如果她的慾望沒有被喚醒，她無法孕育創造。
So, a kalpa is spent in that.
所以，一個劫就在那度過。
Quite a lot of time is spent in Her own thinking – which way She should do it.
她花了相當多的時間在思考——她應該怎麼做。
She has created many universes.
她創造了許多宇宙。
It is not one universe She has created.
她創造的宇宙不止一個。
She has created universes after universes and I will show you how She has created so
她創造了無數的宇宙，我會告訴你她是如何創造
many universes.
這許多的宇宙。
And some of them are still lingering on, some of them are destroyed.
有些仍然存在，有些已被摧毀。
But today before us: this Universe, this Earth, on this Earth, India and in India, Delhi,
今天在我們面前：這個宇宙，這個地球，在這個地球上，印度，在印度，德里，
you are sitting attending this place.
你們現在坐在這裡。
It’s like that.
就是這樣。
So, at this moment, whatever is the thing, is not the past, nor the future, but I’m
所以，在這一刻，無論什麼，都不是過去，也不是未來，而是
telling you about the present moment we are here.
我正在告訴你 我們在這裡的當下時刻。
But many universes have been created by Adi Shakti; even before us.
太初之母已經創造了許多宇宙，甚至在我們之前。
And She has tried many other things also.
她也嘗試過許多其他的創造。
Ultimately She has tried this.
最終她嘗試了這個。
She has created Earth and then created us.
她創造了地球，然後創造了我們人類。
Now, how She has done that we’ll see later on.
我們稍後會看到她是怎麼做到的。
Just now let us see how She assumes her powers.
現在讓我們看看她是如何運用她的力量的。
When She decides to create, She is endowed with three powers: She has three powers of
當她決定創造時，她被賦予三種力量：她擁有
God which are granted to Her.
上帝給她的三種力量。
By one power, first of all, is the existence, the desire to exist, She desires to exist
首先是存在的力量，存在的願望，她渴望
with God.
與上帝同在。
The second power is to create and the third power is to sustain.
第二種力量是創造，第三種力量是維持。
First power is existence, second is to create and the third is the evolving power or sustenance
第一個力量是存在，第二個是創造，第三個是進化的力量或維持的力量，
power by which gradually you sustain something and you become something.
透過第三個力量 逐漸地 你維持 然後進化。
These are the three powers She assumes.
這是她所賦予的三種力量。
In short, we can say that She forms three powers of Mahakali, Mahasaraswati and Mahalakshmi.
簡而言之，我們可以說她形成了三種力量：摩訶迦利(左脈女神)、摩訶莎维德麗(右脈女神)和摩訶拉希什米(中脈女神)。
These are the three powers She assumes within Herself.
這些是她內部所擁有的三種力量。
Now, She uses again Her parabolic systems.
然後，她再次使用她的拋物線系統。
You know, supposing, I have come to this house by this way, I know this way.
如同，假設我是這樣來到這個房子，我知道這條路。
Then I take that way, I know that way.
然後我走那條路，我知道那條路。
I know the middle way, everything.
我知道中間的路，所有的路線都知道。
Now, I know these three ways and I know all about it: with that knowledge, I can do something
現在，我知道這三條路，一清二楚：有了這個知識，我可以做些
else.
其他的事情。
So, She again uses Her parabolic movements.
所以，她再次使用她的拋物線運動。
Actually, Her three movements, of Mahakali, Mahalakshmi and Mahasaraswati, are all the
實際上，她的三個動作，摩訶迦利、摩訶拉希什米和摩訶莎维德麗，始終
time with Her, with the Adi Shakti.
與她、與太初之母在一起。
She can separate them and put them into three different channels.
她可以將它們分開並放入三個不同的通道中。
She can combine them and synthesise them and use it as a parabola – you understand this?
她也可以將它們結合並合成，並將其用作拋物線——你明白嗎？
That’s why when we put a bandhan to you, we say “put a parabola,” is a parabola,
這就是為什麼當我們對你加班單時，我們說“放置一個拋物線”，是一個拋物線，
because the vibrations are all in… all the three powers are flowing this way.
因為生命能量都……這三種力量都是這樣流動的。
So, we have got, you know that, three powers – the Mahakali power you can say, I need
所以，我們有，你知道的，三種力量——其中的摩訶迦利(掌管左脈的女神)，我不需要寫下“摩訶迦利力量”。
not write, “Mahakali power”.
我不需要寫下“摩訶迦利力量”。
By Mahakali power She desires, as I’ve told you, is the emotional side of God, you can
透過摩訶迦利的力量，祂渴望，正如我告訴你的，是上帝的情感面。
say.
你可以這麼說。
She represents the emotional side of God, She desires.
祂代表了上帝的情感面，祂會渴望。
Is the desire is that of God.
這個渴望是上帝的渴望。
God Almighty, Who is the spectator, He is the Sakshi.
全能上帝，祂是見證者，祂是神力。
And She puts that Sakshi into your heart, She reflects that into your heart which is
她將見證者放進你的心中，將那反映在你心中的東西反射出來，
kept all the time burning to watch what you are doing.
並一直保持燃燒，觀看你在做什麼。
To see your play after your creation.
即是創作之後觀看"你"的作品。
Her Mahasaraswati power, now, moves in a parabola.
而摩訶莎维德麗(掌管右脈的女神)力量，現在以一個拋物線運行。
She can move in any angle, 360 angles She can move, from one point.
祂可以從任何角度移動，360 度，祂可以從一個點移動。
Sometimes, She goes round and round at a point.
有時，祂會在一個點上繞來繞去。
When She goes round and round at a point, Her Mahasaraswati power can get consolidated;
當祂在一個點上繞來繞去時，祂的摩訶莎维德麗力量可以得到鞏固；
you can say, it becomes dense.
或者說，祂變得很密集。
You see, that’s the trouble with English language!
用英語不容易表達！
It becomes dense, it becomes so very dense that it cracks out.
祂變得很密集，變得非常密集以至於會裂開。
These cracks occur due to the momentum of the movement of the Mahakali power, Mahasaraswati
這些裂縫的產生是由於摩訶迦利以及摩訶莎维德麗力量力量運動的動力所致。
power.
動力所致。
Because it is moving in a round and round fashion, they also get into the momentum of
因為它以圓形的方式運動，所以它們也進入了動量中
that movement, they start moving.
因為那個動量，他們開始移動。
For example, this part starts moving, this part starts moving, this part starts moving.
就好像，這部分開始移動，這部分開始移動，這部分開始移動。
And when they start moving, they become rounds, they lose their angularities and then they
當他們開始移動時，他們變得圓滑，失去了角度，然後他們
become round.
變得圓潤。
Now I’m telling you, very much in short because it’s a…they become round.
我現在告訴你的，是非常簡短地，因為它們變得圓潤。
These rounds again are put into friction with each other.
這些圓形再次相互摩擦。
And that is how, we can say – now forget about other universes, where other styles
這就是我們現在可以說——不要去想用其他風格創造過的其他的宇宙，
were also created – but about this one we can say, was created.
但關於這個宇宙，我們可以說，它是如此被創造出來的。
Now, you must all the time remember that this Power thinks, understands, organises, loves
現在，你們必須時刻記住，這個力量會思考、理解、組織、愛。
and is an identity.
並是一種身份。
So, She creates the Earth.
所以，祂創造了地球。
Earth is not created so easily.
地球並不是那麼容易被創造的。
Part of the Sun is removed just like this, with the hand, you can say.
太陽的一部分就是這樣被移除的，用手就可以說。
We must understand why the Sun became so cold.
我們必須理解為什麼太陽變得如此寒冷。
Sun is, from the Sun it is removed very much far away first, to the farthest point so that
太陽是，從移除太陽的距離非常遙遠，首先到達最遠的點，所以
it freezes completely.
使其完全凍結。
Also like Moon, it was taken very far away.
就像月球一樣，它被帶得非常遠。
It just freezes completely and is then brought near the Sun again, like a pendulum.
所以它完全凍結，然後又像擺錘一樣被帶回靠近太陽。
It is moved again towards the cold side, again it is brought to the hot side.
它再次移向冷的一側，然後又被帶到熱的一側。
It is brought to a point, to the medium point where Earth is made, is made – again I’m
它被帶到一個點，這個點是地球形成的中間點，這是 – 我再次說，
saying, it’s not a chance of nature – is made deliberately, habitable for human beings,
這不是大自然的偶然——是有意為之，為人類帶來了
the temperature was brought in.
適宜居住的溫度。
It has been done by Adi Shakti, the Mother.
這是由太初之母，聖母完成的。
She has done it deliberately, it’s not easy to conceive of such a Mother.
祂特意來完成這個創造，想像誕生這樣的母親並不容易。
But She has done it.
但她已經做到了。
And She brings this Earth to a point where life can begin.
祂將這個地球帶到一個生命可以開始的點。
So the combination of Moon and the combination of Sun gives you hydrogen from the Moon, oxygen
經由月球和太陽的組合帶來了,月亮的氫，
from the sun, gives you water, the freezing and heating.
太陽的氧氣,而這帶來了水，可以凍結和加熱。
The freezing and heating gives you the water.
冷凍和加熱的過程提供了水。
In the water, when the Earth is made, spirally, to move upward, again the heating and cooling
在水中，當地球以螺旋式向上移動時，加熱和冷卻過程再次開始。
starts.
再次開始。
By heating and cooling, life comes into being as amino-acids.
透過加熱和冷卻，生命以氨基酸的形式形成。
Is done deliberately!
這過程是費心盡力設計來完成的！
What I am saying: it is not done by something, by chance.
我要說的是：地球的創造並不是偶然機率造成的。
On this also one has to think once: “How is it?”
人們必須想一想：“這是怎麼回事？”
It is not chance!
這一切不是偶然！
If you read Du Nouy [Pierre Lecomte Du Nouy (1883-1947)] , is a very big biologist, I
如果你讀杜諾伊（皮埃爾·勒孔特·杜諾伊，1883-1947），他是一位非常偉大的生物學家，
mean, I think he’s one of the greatest biologists who has really gone into the calculations
我認為他是最偉大的生物學家之一，他真的深入研究了計算了
of how much time should it take for a simple amoeba to be created out of the matter and
從物質中創造出一個簡單的阿米巴原蟲需要多長時間，
he has calculated that it should take much more time than even what we have had so far
他計算出這需要比我們迄今為止所經歷的時間更長久許多許多
– billions of billions of years are needed just by chance.
– 數十億年的時間只是偶然的。
Law of chance is there, which I don’t know if I should tell you elaborately, but law
機會法則是存在的，我不知道是否應該詳細告訴你，但機會法則是，
of chance is that, if you have in one tube 50 red pebbles and 50 white pebbles and if
如果你在一個管子裡有50個紅色卵石和50個白色卵石，
you start shaking them and make them absolutely in a chaotic order, it takes so much, so much
如果你開始搖晃它們並使它們完全處於混亂的順序，那麼需要花費很多很多次
times shaking to make it again the same as it is, or to bring it into order.
的搖晃才能使其恢復原樣，或者使其恢復正常。
So, even to create an orderly living protoplasm, a cell, would have taken much more time than
因此，即使是創造一個有序的活原生質，一個細胞，也需要比迄今為止花費更多的時間：
it has taken so far: much more, many times more, billions of billions.
更多，許多倍，數十億。
And it has taken only 5 billion years for Earth to secede from the Moon.
地球從月球脫離只花了50億年。
And only 2 billion years for it to cool down.
而且只花了 20 億年讓它冷卻下來。
So, he says, it is beyond any understanding – only thing that can explain it, what we
所以，他說，這是無法理解的——唯一可以解釋的，我們能說的是，
can say, is that there is a ‘Juggler’ behind it.
它背後有一個「變戲法的人」。
And there is a Juggler, about which our great rishis and munis know that – that Juggler
而這位變戲法的人,我們偉大的智者和修行者都知道——那位魔術師。
is nobody else but Adi Shakti, the Primordial Mother.
不是別人，正是太初之母，太初聖母。
The Primordial Father is Sadashiva and the Primordial Mother is Adi Shakti.
太初之父是全能主，太初聖母是太初之母。
And are we going to discuss about their sex?
而我們要討論他們的性嗎？
Are we going to do that way with the tantrikas?
我們要用密宗這種方式來應對嗎？
Is that the way to pay homage to your parents?
這是向父母致敬的方式嗎？
We have to understand that it’s a very, very solemn subject, we are discussing here
我們必須理解，這是一個非常非常嚴肅的話題，我們在這裡討論
the sanctum sanctorium of the love of our Primordial Parents.
的是我們太初父母(創造者)之愛的聖所。
It’s a very, very holy thing.
這是一件非常非常神聖的事情。
We are not holy people, we are yet full of lots of greed and lust, but they are above
我們不是神聖的人，我們仍然充滿了貪婪和慾望，但祂們高於一切。
everything.
所有一切。
So, when we are discussing them, we have to know, we have to do it with great shraddha,
所以，當我們討論創造者時，我們必須知道，我們必須以極大的虔誠來進行，
and with our head bowed before them that it is our luck and we are very fortunate that
我們低頭向祂們致敬，感謝祂們的恩賜，
we have been able to learn something about these two Primordial Parents who have brought
讓我們有機會了解這兩位創造萬物、孕育他們孩子的太初父母。
forth this Creation, their child.
這個創造的產物。
So, one of these then again cracks and becomes a surya-mandal, and a surya-mandala has got,
所以，這其中的一個再次裂開，變成了一個太陽系，而太陽系，
as you know, Earth and Moon and all these things and I have told you how Earth is created.
正如你所知，包含地球和月球以及所有這些，我已經告訴你地球是如何創造的。
After the Creation of Earth, first, you know that amino-acids were formed, the vegetation
在地球創造之後，首先，你知道氨基酸形成了，植物開始出現
started and then the human being started.
然後人類開始出現。
Now, the matter, also, is a very systematic thing.
現在，物質,也是一個非常系統化的事件。
Matter is not unsystematic, it is systematic, but it is not organised – there is difference
物質不是無系統的，它是有系統的，但它並不是有組織的——
between the two.
這是有區別的。
The systematic things are dead, can be dead.
系統性的事物是死的，可以是死的。
You can put five stones here in a systematic manner, but they are not organised, because
你可以以系統的方式在這裡放五顆石頭，但它們並沒有組織，因為
they are not living things.
它們不是生物。
There’s a difference between the two.
兩者之間是有區別的。
So, first, the systematic things were laid down.
首先，系統性的事物被確立下來。
Perhaps, if you know about the…Eight different types of elements were created.
或許，如果你知道……八種不同類型的元素被創造出來。
These were created and were put into proper places through Shri Ganesha.
這些是通過格泥沙(象神)創造的，並被放置在適當的位置。
You know that the carbon… carbon is in the centre of these periodical elements that appear.
你知道碳……碳位於這些出現的周期元素的中心。
That means a element which has got one valency, two valency, three valency and four valency,
這意味著一種元素具有一價、二價、三價和四價，
the three are the plus ones, then you’ve got one C, carbon, which has got four valences.
三個是加一，然後你有一個 C，碳，具有四個價電子。
Then you have got, again, minus one, two, three and four – is a complete eight.
然後你有，依然是負一、二、三和四——所以是一個完整的八。
Like that, the whole matter has been organised.
就這樣，整個物質已經被組織起來了。
To organise the matter, some deity was to be created for that, and first deity that
為了組織這些物質，必須創造神祈，而第一位被創造的神祈是
was created was that of Shri Ganesh.
格泥沙(象神)
Let us see now how She created here.
現在讓我們看看太初之母是如何創造格泥沙的。
You have seen that one part of Her, which is the Mahasaraswati, has created the matter.
你已經看到了她的一部分，即摩訶莎维德麗，她創造了物質。
Mahasaraswati has created the matter.
摩訶莎维德麗創造了物質。
Now, Mahakali has to give them existence.
現在，摩訶迦利必須賦予它們存在。
How do you get an existence?
你如何獲得存在？
Is through your sustenance or, you can say, through your quality – whatever you are.
是透過你的存有，或者說，是透過你的特質——無論你是什麼。
So, Mahakali gives that existence to those material things, not human beings or living
所以，摩訶迦利透過格泥沙(象神)將這種存有賦予那些物質事物，不是人類或生物，
things but matter, through a deity known as Shri Ganesh.
而是物質。
Mahakali…
摩訶迦利…
In the heart of the Viraata, as you see, – you’ll see Viraata also He comes in, because that
在宇宙大我的中心，如你所見，– 你會看到宇宙大我也進來，因為那
I will tell you later on – but in the heart of Viraata, is the Primordial Being, the complete
我稍後會告訴你，但在宇宙大我的中心，是原始存有，
Primordial Being, the Mahakali is settled down.
完整的原始存有，摩訶迦利已經安定下來。
What She does, She goes three and a half from the heart: one up, one down like that – three
她所做的，就是從心臟出發三圈半的距離：一個向上，一個向下，就這樣:
and a half times and comes to the end of the three and a half, down-way.
三又二分之一，最後回到三又二分之一的末端，向下方向。
Three and a half.
三又二分之一。
Now, She comes at the end of it.
現在，她來到它的末端。
And if you put three and a half like that and if you cut it straight, you get 7 centres
如果你把三又二分之一這樣放，然後把它直線切開，你會得到7個切面。
cut in.
切面。
Is there a drawing person who knows how to draw?
有沒有會畫畫的人？
You should start from like that, you can put it like this.
你應該從這裡開始，你可以這樣畫。
She comes down here.
她從這裡下來。
She comes down here and from here She penetrates.
她下來這裡，然後從這裡她進入。
You see, She cuts at seven points here.
你看，她在這裡切了七個點。
At this point, She creates the first deity, little below, of Shri Ganesh.
在這一點上，她創造了第一位神祇，位於下方的象神格泥沙。
I mean, this is not done in one day, is not done in one year, not done in one Yuga, it
我的意思是，這不是一天內完成的，也不是一年內完成的，不是一個循環時代內完成的。
is done in many Kalpas.
而是歷經許多宇宙週期完成。
The first step is to create Shri Ganesh, this is Her abode and She puts Shri Ganesh.
第一步是創造格泥沙，這是她的居所，她將格泥沙放這。
Now, he is emitting his vibrations through all this.
現在，格泥沙通過這一切發出祂的生命能量。
He passes through all this whatever She has created.
祂通過她所創造的一切。
On this picture is settled the work of the Mahasaraswati, you can say.
這個圖上展現了摩訶莎维德麗的工作，可以這麼說。
She comes down with all Her programs like this and She makes it.
她帶著所有的計劃像這樣推出來，然後實現它。
And She gets joined here again.
她再次在這裡加入。
So, Shri Ganesh emits His vibrations through her.
所以，格泥沙通過摩訶莎维德麗發出祂的生命能量。
First, Shri Mahakali creates Shri Ganesh and then Mahasaraswati comes down, She creates
首先，摩訶迦利創造了象神格泥沙，然後摩訶莎维德麗降臨，她創造了
all these things and gets connected to Shri Ganesh.
這一切並與象神格泥沙建立連結。
So, the vibrations of Shri Ganesh start flowing through all the creation of Mahasaraswati.
所以，格泥沙的生命能量開始流經摩訶莎维德麗的所有創造。
Before creating all this, the complete thought of what is going to happen in future comes
在創造這一切之前，對未來將要發生的一切的完整想法
in a clear-cut vision of the Adi Shakti.
都呈現在太初之母的清晰願景。
And She puts Her plans through.
她將她的計劃付諸實行。
First of all, the Mahalakshmi power comes down and creates the Shri Ganesh.
首先，摩訶拉希什米的力量降臨並創造了格泥沙。
You can understand now how important it is that we have to be holy people.
你現在可以理解為什麼我們必須成為聖潔的人 這有多重要。
First, She created the holiness on this Earth.
首先，她在這個地球上創造了神聖。
First thing, Her relationship with the child was established, because the Creation is going
首先，她與孩子的關係已經建立起來，
to be created in the image of Her child.
因為創造將按照她孩子的形象創造出來。。
That’s why Shri Ganesh was created first.
這就是為什麼格泥沙首先被創造出來。
And then from here, say, is the Adi Shakti, the other power, Mahasaraswati, on Her way,
然後從這裡說，是太初之母，另一種力量，摩訶莎维德麗，在前往的路上，
She comes down and gets connected with Shri Ganesh.
她下來並與格泥沙連接。
And that’s how the Shri Ganesh establishes the relationship and emits His vibrations
這就是格泥沙如何建立關係並通過這個
through this.
發出祂的生命能量。
Because of His vibrations passing through the matter that She has created.
因為祂的生命能量穿過她所創造的物質。
For example, our Mother Earth: through this passes the, you know that through it passes
例如，我們的大地母親：通過這裡，您知道它通過的
the axis.
軸心。
Nobody has seen the axis, but they say, there is an axis, from the way it moves.
沒有人見過軸心，但他們說，從地球運轉的方式來看，確實存在一個軸心。
There is a kind of an axis.
有一種軸心。
Now, this is the power of Mahakali passing through the [axis].
現在，這是摩訶迦利的力量通過這個[軸心]。
We can say, it’s the power of Shri Ganesh passing through the axis of the Mother Earth,
我們可以說，這是格泥沙的力量穿過地球的軸心,
which has got magnetic power in it.
而其中具有磁力。
And that’s how, through that, it controls its speed, its movement, and also it looks
而這就是祂如何通過這個軸心來控制速度、運轉，
after us.
以及照顧我們。
Why don’t we think that when we put a little seed in the soil it sprouts, automatically?
為什麼我們不曾思考 為什麼當我們把一粒小種子放進土壤中時，它會自動發芽呢？
You have seen now, many of you who have been suffering from certain troubles and diseases,
你們中許多人現在已經看到了，那些曾經遭受某些困擾和疾病，
that the Mother Earth herself took down your problems, She sucked them out.
大地母親吸走了你們的問題，她把問題吸出來了。
It is a fact, you can see it in Sahaja Yoga, that after realisation if you have any problem,
這是一個事實，你可以在霎哈嘉瑜伽中看到，得到自覺後如果你有任何問題，
if your head is heavy, if you are a realised soul, otherwise She doesn’t listen, because
如果你的頭很重，如果你是一個自覺靈，否則她不會幫，因為
you should be activated or you should be granted a certificate from the Adi Shakti that you’re
你應該被啟動，或者你應該從太初之母那裡獲得證書，證明你是
a realised person, otherwise why should She accept you?
一個有自覺的人，否則她為什麼要接受你呢？
You just put your head on the soil, put your both the hands on the Mother Earth and you’ll
你只需把頭放在大地，雙手放在大地上，你就會
find the whole thing will be sucked out from your forehead.
發現所有負面會從你的額頭被吸走。
It has been done with many, even from the legs it can take out.
這已經在許多人身上發生過，甚至可以從腿也可以。
Mother Earth is actually, is the Mother of Adi Shakti, you can say.
大地母親實際上是太初之母的母親，你可以這麼說。
She is the Mother, they say, because She is made in such a way that She takes all the
她被稱為母親，因為她的構造使她能夠承受所有
weights of the world in Herself.
世界的重擔。
She controls all the weights of the world and She can consume all your weight.
她控制著世界上所有的重擔，並且她可以消耗你身上的重擔。
She’s the dharaa.
她是大地。
Now, weight means everything that… your weight is what we weigh in: that’s not the
現在，重擔表示所有……不是我們所理解的：不是
thing.
一般。
Weight means also your sins, also your punyas.
重擔代表你的罪，也代表著你的積德。
It means everything.
它代表一切。
If you have too many sins in you, then Mother Earth feels hurt.
如果你犯了太多罪，那麼大地母親會感到受傷。
Wherever there is too much of sin, then Mother Earth has to ask help.
無論在哪裡有過多的罪，大地母親都必須尋求幫助。
And then some other deity has to, like Vishnu himself, has to come on this Earth to save
然後其他神祈，比如毗濕奴本人，就必須降世來到這個世界
Her from this too much of overloading of sins upon this Earth.
拯救她免於過多罪的負擔。
Is a fact!
這是一個事實！
It is not I’m telling you a mythical story, is a fact.
我不是在告訴你一個神話故事，而是一個事實。
Which you have to verify after getting vibrations.
你必須在感受到生命能量後來驗證。
Before getting vibrations, you cannot find out from the Mother Earth.
在獲得生命能量之前，你無法從大地母親那裡找到答案。
If you want to find out some time, if you are realised, you just stand on the Mother
如果你想知道何時才能自覺，如果你已得自覺，你只需站在大地上，
Earth and ask her “Will you take away my sins, oh Mother Earth?
請問她 「大地母親啊，你能帶走我的罪嗎？
Will you take away my karmas?
可以請你帶走我的業力嗎？
I have been realised."
我是個有自覺的靈。"
Immediately, She’ll start drawing you.
她會立即開始取出。
You’ll be surprised.
你會感到驚訝。
You’ll feel so much lighter.
你會感覺輕鬆很多。
You have to use Her.
你必須傾用她。
That is how Mother Earth has been created.
這就是大地母親如何被創造的。
But also Adi Shakti through Her Mahasaraswati power has created the five elements.
太初之母通過她的摩訶莎维德麗力量創造了五大元素。
Before everything else, She created tanmatra (subtle elements) as you call it, I mean,
在一切之前，祂創造了你所稱的精微元素，我的意思是，
if I go into details, it’s going to be too much for you!
如果我再詳細說明，對你來說會太多了！
But first of all, the causal essences were created by Her.
首先，因果的本質是祂創造的。
But if I say like this, there won’t be anything false.
如果我這樣說，就不會有任何虛假。
If I say that just by seeing by Her sight, by her drushti (sight), She has created this
如果我說僅僅通過她的視線，她的視線，她創造了
light.
光。
Just by Her breathing, She has created air, because Her desire is the last point.
通過她的呼吸，她創造了空氣，因為她的渴望是重點。
Because She desired there should be air, She created air.
因為她希望有空氣，所以她創造了空氣。
Like that, She has, Her smell has created the causal, gandha, which has created this
就像那樣，她的氣味創造了因果，這芬香創造了這個
mother Earth.
大地母親。
And it has started from Her only, from Her desires, by Her desiring it – it was created
這一切都是從祂開始，從祂的渴望開始，因為祂的渴望而創造出來的。
for Her and that’s how it was created in the whole Universe, which was later on made
因為她，這就是整個宇宙是如何創造的，後來創造了
into Earth, Moon, Sun and all these things.
地球、月亮、太陽和這些所有事物。
Actually, it was Her mere desire which brought forth these.
實際上，正是因為祂的渴望帶來了創造。
For us it is impossible to understand someone like that, who, just by mere desire can create.
對我們來說，是不可能去理解這樣的人，因為僅憑藉願望就能創造。
But when we think of somebody who is above all the powers of the world, the One the,
但是當我們想到某個超越所有世界的力量的存在時，那
who is the highest of all: She can do anything She feels like.
是所有中最高的：祂可以做任何祂想做的事情。
Can’t we think like that?
我們可以這樣想嗎？
We cannot think of someone like that.
我們無法想像有人是有這樣的力量。
We think of God, who is Almighty, we call Him, but when we talk of His mights we start
我們想到全能上帝，我們稱呼祂，但當我們談論祂的威能時，我們開始
laughing.
笑。
How can it be?
這怎麼可能？
But She can do anything She wants to.
祂可以做任何祂想做的事。
It is only Her mere desire that has brought forth all these creations and all this things
只有祂的渴望才帶來了所有這些創造和這一切事物
that you see in this world are created only by Her desire.
所有你在這個世界上看到的 都是由祂的渴望創造的。
She created akasha.
她創造了空間。
She created all these five elements, which you know, and then She started Her another
她創造了五個元素，你知道的，然後她開始了她的另一個
form which we call as the Mahalakshmi form.
形式，我們稱之為摩訶拉希什米形式。
Before that, I think, I should tell you about Shri Ganesha’s existence in the matter.
在此之前，我想我應該告訴你有關格泥沙(像神)在物質中的存在。
He acts in the matter as vibrations, as Mahasaraswati vibrations.
祂在物質呈現為生命能量，視為摩訶莎维德麗的生命能量。
They are electromagnetic vibrations, Mahasaraswati vibrations are electromagnetic vibrations,
它們是電磁振波，摩訶莎维德麗的生命能量是電磁振波，
we can say, that electromagnetic and also there is sound, and all these five elements
我們可以說，這是電磁的，有聲音，以及這五種元素
are expressed in that.
都體現在其中。
You can record them – because if you take a sulphur dioxide, for example, a sulphur
你可以記錄它們——因為如果你拿二氧化硫為例，一個硫
dioxide and two oxygen and one sulphur and if you watch them properly under a very highly
和兩個氧，如果你在非常高度微觀下仔細觀察它們，
micro – you can try, I don’t know if people have tried, but you can try to find out – and
– 你可以試，我不知道人們是否試過，但你可以試著找出來 –
put it under, let’s say, a very highly developed micro – microwave- microscope, you can say,
把它放在一個非常高度發展的微波 – 顯微鏡下，你可以說，
you can see that the oxygen things and sulphur, – sulphur is stationary, – but these two
你可以看到氧和硫，– 硫是靜止的，– 但這兩個
are vibrating.
會產生振波。
They are vibrating, there’s a vibration going between these bonds.
它們會振動，這些鍵之間存有一種振波。
They can be isometric also, they can be symmetric, they can be even, uneven and they can be expanding,
它們也可以是等距的，可以是對稱的，可以是偶數，不是偶數，也可以擴展，
and closing like that.
和閉合。
So, there are three types of vibrations, we find.
所以，我們發現有三種類型的生命能量。
And the fourth side is nothing but Shri Ganesha himself who is controlling.
而第四方面正是掌控一切的象神格泥沙本人。
So, this we can see with our naked eyes, if you want to see, even if you are realised
這是我們可以用肉眼看到的，如果你想看的話，
or not.
無論你是否有自覺。
From where do these vibrations come in the minutest paramanu, as you call, the molecules?
這些生命能量是從哪裡來的，最微小的 paramanu，正如你所說的，分子？
In a molecule, how do you get these vibrations, can you explain this?
在一個分子中，這些生命能量是如何產生的，你能解釋一下嗎？
It is so much, sukshma, parasukshma.
這是如此精微，極度精微。
The powers of Ganesha are very, very subtle and they enter into the matter and create
格泥沙的力量非常非常精微，它們進入物質並創造
this kind of vibrations, which you can even see and record, electromagnetic vibrations,
這種生命能量，你甚至可以看到並記錄下來，電磁振波，
in, even, a one small, little molecule.
即使在一個小小的分子中。
So, we have in these, as I told you, into the periodic level, periodic laws of elements,
所以，正如我告訴你的，我們在這些元素的週期性層面上，週期律中，
you can find out that all the elements are divided into eight types.
你可以發現所有的元素被分為八種類型。
Just see!
看看吧！
How can all the elements be divided into eight parts without somebody being there?
怎麼能把所有元素分成八個部分，如果不是因為有某人在運作呢？
Can you do something without organising a proper chart of these elements?
如果不組織這些元素的適當​​圖表，你可以做任何事嗎？
Just think about it!
想想看吧！
You see, when we challenge God, we have to understand that in this world everything is
當我們挑戰上帝時，我們必須明白，在這個世界上，一切都是井然有序的，
so well organised, there are eight elements spread out so well, placed so well.
有八個元素分佈得如此好，放置得如此好。
And it has a particular style of behaviour and every element is different in numbers
And it has a particular style of behaviour and every element is different in numbers
and protons and these numbers are very well calculated in such a manner that the end of
這些數字的計算方式非常好，以至於它的結尾，最後一個圓，
it, that the last circle, that the last circle of all the protons should be eight.
所有質子的最後一個圓都是八。
If it is not eight, if it is less than eight then it creates a valency problem.
如果它不是八，如果它小於八，那麼就會產生化合價問題。
It is so well organised, then, even if you study this, if there is anybody who knows
它組織得非常好，即使你學習它，如果有人懂一點化學，
little bit of chemistry, you know, so if you know chemistry, it’s such a wonderful thing.
你知道，所以如果你懂化學，那是一件很棒的事情。
We take it for granted!
我們把這視為理所當然！
We think it is our right to have the matter so well organised for us!
我們認為我們有權利要求把這件事安排得如此妥當！
But the valencies are all depending on such a nice organisation of this eight protons
但是，所有價態都取決於外層
at the outer thing.
這八個質子的良好排列。
This is all done through the Mahasaraswati power.
這一切都是通過摩訶莎维德麗的力量完成的。
But the vibrating force…Now see, there is a vibrating force: this is all done through
但是電磁振波的力量……這是一種振動的力量：這一切都是通過
the, as I told you, through the Mahasaraswati power.
正如我告訴你的，通過摩訶莎维德麗的力量完成的。
She creates.
她創造。
Now the vibrating force: He exists, matter also exists.
現在的振動波力量：他存在，物質也存在。
It must exist.
它一定存在。
If it does not exist, nothing can exist.
如果它不存在，什麼都無法存在。
So, the existence force is given through the Mahakali force, which is acting through Shri
因此，存在的力量是通過摩訶迦利來賦予，而摩訶迦利的力量是透過位於核心的
Ganesh, who is sitting at the nucleus.
象神格泥沙來發揮作用的。
He is sitting at the nucleus of every [atom].
他位於每個原子核的中心。
Can you imagine how much it must be?
你能想像這有多少嗎？
Every molecule and every atom.
每一個分子和每一個原子。
You cannot understand the finiteness of it.
你無法理解它的有限性。
Now, see, say, take one element like gold, how many molecules it has?
例如說，拿一種元素，比如金，這有多少個分子？
Can you calculate?
你能計算嗎？
[It’s] beyond us!
[這] 超出我們的能力！
How many, you can say, atoms it has?
你能說它有多少個原子嗎？
We just cannot calculate it.
我們根本無法計算。
And then how many Ganesha’s pictures must be there?
那麼，那裡應該有多少張格泥沙的相片呢？
How is it achieved?
這是如何達成的？
Is another thing which I will tell you if I come in the way.
如果我到那，我會告訴你另一件事。
How infinite reflections are caught into and why there are two things like Shiva and Adi
無限的反射是如何產生的？以及為什麼會有像上帝和太初之母
Shakti?
這兩個身分?
The reason is it has to create an infinite reflection.
原因是它必須創造一個無限的反射。
How do you create an infinite reflection?
你要怎麼創造一個無限的反射？
Do you know that?
你知道嗎？
Anybody who knows physics?
有誰懂物理學？
If you place in the centre of two mirrors something, then the reflections are infinite.
如果你把東西放在兩面鏡子的中心，那麼反射是無限的。
So, the first mirror is the Adi Shakti and the second mirror is this Creation, and that’s
所以，第一面鏡子是太初之母，第二面鏡子是這個創造，這就是
how you can get infinite reflections on this Earth.
你如何在這個地球上獲得無限的反射。
This is the reason why you can get infinite reflections.
這就是為什麼你可以獲得無限反射的原因。
And that’s why you had to create another one who reflects it.
這就是為什麼你必須創造另一個能夠反射的存在。
And that’s why there have to be three identities, one, the God Almighty, then Adi Shakti and
這就是為什麼必須有三個身份，一個是全能上帝，然後是太初之母
then the whole Universe.
然後是整個宇宙。
It had to be that way, otherwise you cannot create infinite reflections.
必須這樣，否則你無法創造無限的反射。
Now, somebody who has done this job must be a very clever man, no doubt.
毫無疑問，能完成這項工作的人一定是一個非常聰明的人。
When human beings think that they can know God through their buddhi, they must know,
當人類認為他們可以通過他們的智慧來認識上帝時，他們必須知道，
how can you reach this Buddhi, it’s supreme.
你如何能夠達到這種智慧，它是至高無上的。
How much labour He has taken to create us!
他為創造我們付出了多少勞力啊！
After creating the matter, then He, or I should say, His power as Mahalakshmi descends on
在創造了物質之後，他，或者我應該說，作為摩訶拉希什米的祂的神力降臨到
this Earth.
這個地球上。
Mahalakshmi helps in sustenance.
摩訶拉希什米幫助維持生存。
Sustenance means all the scanning of all these elements.
維持生存意味著對所有這些元素的進行掃描。
When they create the matter, the matter is differently created, created for different
當他們創造物質時，物質的創造方式是不同的，創造的目的也不同。
purposes.
創造的目的也不同。
Now, what is the ultimate?
那麼，最終的目的是什麼？
The Creation has its ultimate aim is to create human beings – this creation, just imagine!
創造的最終目的是創造人類——這個創造，想像一下！
You people are so great that for you all these troubles have been taken.
你們這些人類真是太棒了，為了你們，所有的這些麻煩都被承受了。
Such an important thing is a human being that all these troubles are taken, – all matter,
人類如此重要，以至於所有這些麻煩——所有物質、所有的一切
all, everything, is used just to create you.
——都被用來創造你們人類。
This is the ultimate aim.
這是最終的目標。
Sort of a stage has to be laid down and you come, the Sahaja Yogis come on the scene,
可以說，需要搭建一個舞台，然後你們，霎哈嘉瑜伽士才會出現。
you can say.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士才會出現。
Just the instrument of man is to be created.
上帝要創造的只是人類的工具。
Now, why God wanted to create an instrument of man?
現在，為什麼上帝要創造人類的工具呢？
Because He wanted to create an instrument which could feel Him, which could understand
因為祂想要創造一個能夠感受祂、理解祂、傳送..
Him, which could emit, like Krishna creating his murli (flute).
就像克里希納創造祂的笛子一樣。
He just wanted to play through our instruments His power.
祂只是想通過我們的樂器來表達他的力量。
But He didn’t want to do it through the dead instruments like these but through the
但祂不想透過死氣沉沉的工具來完成，
living instruments.
而是想透過活生生的工具來完成。
Supposing, if this (microphone) can understand, can love, has a human mind, and if my voice
假設這個（麥克風）能夠理解、能夠愛、擁有人類的思維，
is passing through it like a hollow personality then we can say that this is a realised personality.
如果我的聲音可以穿過這個像笛子的空洞的人格，那麼我們可以說這是一個有自覺的人格。
But this is not a living being, you are a living being.
但這並非一個生命體，你才是。
You are made specially with all these difficulties for millions of years, have been worked out
你是歷經數百萬年的艱辛，被精心打造而成，
so carefully, so delicately, one after another.
每一個細節都經過如此細緻入微的雕琢。
We have to now jump to the evolution part, because you see, it’s a very long thing.
我們現在必須直接進入進化部分，因為，這是一個非常漫長的過程。
Shri Mataji: Kiti wasle (Marathi: what time is it?)
錫呂瑪塔吉: Kiti wasle (馬拉地語：現在幾點了？)
Yogi: Saha wasle (six o’clock)
瑜珈士: Saha wasle (六點鐘)
So, now we have to come to the most important part which is evolution, which we should understand,
所以，現在我們必須談到最重要的部分——演化，我們應該理解它，
because we know evolution through science.
因為我們透過科學來了解演化。
When these three forces came into being, before creating any earth or before creating this
當這三種力量誕生之時，在創造地球、創造宇宙或任何事物之前，
universe or anything, first they had to draw out a proper picture about it and a proper
它們首先必須描繪出一幅清晰的藍圖，
understanding of it, you see.
並對宇宙有充分的理解。
As before doing anything, say, we have to plan out things, we have a planning commission,
就像做任何事情之前，我們都需要規劃，我們會成立一個規劃委員會
first of all, we sit down with a planning commission.
首先要和規劃委員會坐下來討論。
In the same way, first, they had to form a stage where they just plan out the things.
同樣地，它們首先必須建立一個階段，在這個階段裡，它們可以規劃一切。
This stage we can call it as the vaikuntha state.
我們可以把這個階段稱為「外琨塔」（Vaikuntha）。
Because this (current stage) is not the earliest state, this is created later on.
因為（目前的階段）並非最初的狀態，它是後來才形成的。
First, the planning state is known as the vaikuntha state.
首先，規劃狀態稱為毘濕奴界（外琨塔）。
At this stage they created all the incarnations.
在這個階段，他們創造了所有的降世神祈。
Incarnations were not created after the Earth has been created, which is a very wrong idea.
降世神祈並不是在地球創造之後才被創造出來的，這是一個非常錯誤的觀念。
They created all the incarnations at the vaikuntha state.
他們在毘濕奴界創造了所有的降世神祈。
Where you or I never existed at that time, this Earth never existed and nothing existed
在那個時候，你或我都不存在，地球也不存在，什麼都不存在。
that you see with your naked eyes now.
你現在用肉眼所見的一切都不存在。
But a state of existence, the first one, known as the vaikuntha state, existed.
但是，存在著一種最初的狀態，即毘濕奴界。
In that vaikuntha state the planning of the whole Universe and the whole cosmos and all
在毘濕奴界，整個宇宙、整個世界
that was decided.
以及所有事物的規劃都已確定。
So, the first person who had to come on this was Shiva, because without him nothing can
所以，第一個必須出現的是全能主，因為沒有祂萬物都無法存在，
exist, but where to settle Him down, because He is to be reflected onto something.
但要把祂安置在哪裡? 因為祂必須被映照到某個事物上。
If Shiva has to be reflected onto someone, you have to create a reflector.
如果全能主要被映照到某個事物上，就必須創造一個反射體。
So, they had to, first, think of the one Primordial Being or a, one Huge Identity you can call
所以，他們首先必須想到原始存在，或者說一個可以稱為「宇宙大我」
it, known as Viraat.
的偉大存在。
They created Viraata.
他們創造了宇宙大我。
This will be the Viraata, this will be the complete form of the Primordial Being.
這就是宇宙大我，就是原始存在的完整形態。
This is the one I’m telling you about, this Reflector, The First One.
這就是我所說的反射體，第一個反射體。
The God Almighty has to be reflected, so, first, let us create, first of all, the Primordial
全能的神必須被映照，所以，首先，讓我們創造原始存在，
Being, the Viraat.
就是宇宙大我。
In the Viraat they created different incarnations.
在宇宙大我，他們創造了不同的降世神祈。
Incarnations are not created from human beings.
降世神祈不是由人類創造的。
I don’t know why people think like that.
我不明白為什麼人們會這樣想。
They cannot be created by human beings.
降世神祈不可能由人類創造。
But they were first created.
但它們最初是被創造出來的。
You see, evolution is alright from amoeba to human beings, but there is no evolution
你看，從阿米巴到人類的演化是合理的，
for incarnations.
但降世神祈沒有經過進化。
They are made like that from the very beginning.
它們從一開始就是這樣被造的。
As you have seen in the Viraata, I have shown you the picture of the Viraat, the three powers
正如你們在宇宙大我中所見，我已經向你展示了宇宙大我的圖景，三種力量
of Mahakali, Mahalakshmi and Mahasaraswati met at the Agya Chakra, and there they produced
摩訶迦利、摩訶拉希什米和摩訶莎维德麗這三位女神的力量在額輪相遇，然後
two children each – it’s not a story, is a fact, again – as brothers and sisters.
她們各自孕育了兩個孩子——這不是故事，而是事實——他們是兄弟姐妹。
And these brothers and sister means the relationship is of a temporary nature but of a subtler
這種兄弟姐妹的關係意味著她們之間的關係是暫時的，卻蘊含著
temperament.
更微妙的特質。
And then they were married, inter-communication took place.
然後她們都結婚了，並且相互溝通。
Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati and Mahakali created all together six children, who were married.
摩訶拉希什米、摩訶莎维德麗和摩訶迦利共同創造了六個孩子，這些孩子也都結婚了。
Inter-marriage took place.
他們之間通婚。
By that inter-marriage they got an entity which was a kinetic personality and a potential
透過這種通婚，她們獲得了一個擁有動態人格和潛在能量的實體，
energy within it, such a combination.
如此奇妙的組合。
And they placed those incarnations on different chakras.
他們將這些降世神祈放置在不同的脈穴上。
They brought from these, from the top, all of them were brought from the Agya downward
她們從額輪開始，自上而下地將這些降世神祈
and placed onto all the chakras.
安置在所有脈輪上。
These incarnations, as you know, are placed on different chakras of the Viraata.
如你所知，這些降世神祈被安置在宇宙大我的不同脈穴上。
Many people won’t understand this and won’t like to hear this also, because human beings
很多人不會理解這一點，也不願意聽到，
are so egoistical that they cannot understand that there is a God, Who is Almighty, Who
因為人類太過自私，無法理解有一位全能的神，
is going to do everything, He has His own ways of doing it.
祂無所不能，祂有祂自己的行事方式。
Now, whether I’m telling the Truth or not, you can verify it on vibrations.
無論我說的是否屬實，你都可以透過生命能量來驗證。
You can see for yourself how Incarnations were created.
。你可以親眼見證降世神祈是如何被創造的的。
And all these Incarnations were placed in the Viraata state.
所有這些降世神祈都被放置在宇宙大我狀態。
Here, to create the reflection on the other side, Shiva was removed from the Shakti, as
為了在另一側形成鏡像，全能主從神力中被分離出來，
it was removed in the beginning and it was placed on top of the Viraata’s head as the
就像最初那樣，並被放置在宇宙大我的頭頂，
Sadashiva’s peetha.
成為全能主的寶座。
In the same way, we, too, have a Sadashiva’s peetha on our head.
同樣，我們的頭頂也有一個全能主的寶座。
You see, we are the reflection of the reflector.
你看，我們是反射者的鏡像。
So, we, too, have the same style, we, too, have a Sadahsiva’s peetha on our head.
所以，我們也有相同的風格，我們的頭上也有一個全能主的寶座。
He’s also placed here only.
祂也只位於此處。
But when the Kundalini enters into the being, when he is in the womb of the mother, that
But when the Kundalini enters into the being, when he is in the womb of the mother, that
time this Sadashiva peetha, or we can say, Sadashiva from this peetha descends into the
time this Sadashiva peetha, or we can say, Sadashiva from this peetha descends into the
heart.
心臟。
And that’s how you hear the first throb in the heart.
這就是你如何在心臟中聽到第一次跳動的原因。
It is just the same as it happened in the Viraata.
這與在宇宙大我中發生的情況完全相同。
But at the vaikuntha stage this was not created, the second reflector here was not created,
但在外琨塔階段，這並沒有被創造出來，這裡並沒有創造出第二個反射器，
only the first one.
只有第一個反射器被創造出來。
So, only the Viraata was created and in His Being, in the planning stage, first of all,
所以，只有宇宙大我被創造出來，在祂的存在中，在規劃階段，首先，
these officers, you can say, in charge of these chakras were created by Adi Shakti.
這些掌管這些脈穴的「官員」（你可以這麼說）是由太初之母創造的。
God is the witness and She is doing the play and She creates those chakras.
上帝是見證者，她在演繹這一切，並創造那些脈輪穴。
In the chakras She places all these deities to govern.
她將這些神安置在這些脈穴之中，由祂們來掌管一切。
Now, there is the existence, there is the creation, creative force, and there is the
如今，存在著存有，存在著創造，存在著創造力，
evolutionary force – all inside the Viraata state.
存在著進化的力量 - 這一切都存在於宇宙大我狀態之中。
Now, this is at the vaikuntha state, we say, because this state is on this first reflection.
現在，在外琨塔狀態，我們說，因為這個狀態是在這第一個反射上。
It is not in us, or we cannot feel it, the vaikuntha state, because it is in the first
外琨塔的狀態不在我們之內，或者說我們無法感受到它，因為它存在於
thing.
最初的事物之中。
Then another state was created, then third was created.
然後又創造了另一個狀態，接著又創造了第三個狀態。
But the fourth one is the bhavasagara, is the state at which all of us were born.
但第四個是幻海，是我們所有人出生時的狀態。
First, in the fourth state…now, can you think of a four strata personality which is
首先，在第四個狀態……現在，你能想像一個四層人格
facing a mirror?
面對著鏡子嗎？
Now, which is the first one [that] shows?
現在，最先映照出來的是哪一層？
Is the topmost.
是最頂層的。
And that’s why the topmost shows is the bhavasagara.
這就是為什麼最頂層映照出來的是幻海。
But if you can go deep down into your state, you can feel all the other three.
但如果你能深入到你的狀態，你可以感受到其他三層。
But first of all, the one which you can see and feel it, is the bhavasagara.
但首先，你可以看到和感受到的，是幻海。
So, you are born in the bhavasagara.
所以，你出生在幻海。
At this state you are at the bhavasagara state.
在這個狀態下，你處於幻海狀態。
At this bhavasagara state, now, you are created and you have to evolve.
在這個幻海狀態下，你被創造出來，你必須進化。
At this time the Mahalakshmi power acts to evolve you.
此時，摩訶拉希什米的力量會發揮作用，促使你進化。
You already know how evolutionary things have taken place but I will tell you how evolution
你已經知道進化是如何發生的，但我會根據我們的往世書（Puranas，古代經文）
has taken place according to our puranas (ancient scriptures), and which is a fact.
來告訴你進化是如何發生的，這都是事實。
The Evolution of Man started, first from the amoeba, you can say; because the life came
可以說，人類的演化始於變形蟲；因為生命誕生於水中，
into being into water, as I told you [that] first the water was created.
正如我之前所說，水是先被創造出來的。
In the water the amino-acids were formed, amoeba were formed, fishes were formed and
在水中，胺基酸形成，變形蟲形成，魚類形成。
fishes, when they were formed, they found, the smaller fishes found it difficult to exist
魚類形成後，它們發現小魚生存艱難，
because of the bigger fishes were trying to eat it.
因為大魚總是試圖捕食它們。
It comes as a reciprocal thing, they were absolutely fed up of this destruction that
這是一種互惠互利的關係，它們對這種不斷發生的破壞
was going on.
感到厭倦。
At this time, Shri Vishnu Himself, the One who is the evolutionary force, descended on
此時，作為進化之力的毘濕奴神
this Earth as the Matsya-Avatara.
化身為魚神降臨人間。。
He helped some of the fishes to cross across the shores.
他幫助一些魚渡過海岸。
By crossing across they had that courage, She was the leader.
魚兒們憑藉著勇氣渡過，他是領頭的。
And then others started crossing across.
之後，其他的魚也開始渡河。
This was the first evolutionary stage which we know.
這就是我們所知的第一個進化階段。。
These fishes became reptiles later on; as you know, in the evolutionary stages that
這些魚類後來變成了爬行動物；正如你所知，在進化過程中
they became reptiles.
它們變成了爬蟲類。
But how did they become reptiles?
但他們是怎麼變成爬蟲類的？
There must be someone who must have given them the lead.
一定有人引導了他們。
It was again Shri Vishnu, who came on this Earth as a Kurma and lots of things were done
這個人正是毘濕奴，他以龜的形態降臨人間。
at this time in the vaikuntha stage, before He came on this Earth as a Kurma Avatara.
在毘濕奴化身為龜之前，在外琨塔階段發生了很多事情。
At the vaikuntha stage, when they created this Earth, when they created, they planned
在外琨塔階段，當他們創造這個地球時，他們規劃了
this whole Viraata and wanted to create, on this side of the reflector the whole planning
整個宇宙大我，並希望在反射器的這一側創造。
and the whole thinking and all that process brought forth some sort of a waste matter.
所有的規劃、思考以及整個過程產生了一些廢棄物。。
It brought forth the waste matter.
帶來了廢棄物。
This waste matter got contaminated or, we can say, got stagnated on to one side which
這些廢棄物被污染了，或者我們可以說，停滯在被忽視的一側。
was neglected somehow, and through it started coming out some satanic forces and there was
並由此滋生出一些邪惡勢力，
a big fight between the satanic forces and the good forces.
引發了邪惡勢力與正義勢力之間的大戰。
It actually happened in the third stage, not at the vaikuntha stage, but at the third stage,
這實際上發生在第三階段，而不是在外琨塔階段，而是在第三階段，
because when the planning started, the working out started, these satanic forces started
因為當計畫開始、行動開始時，這些邪惡勢力也開始變得
working out.
活耀。
Now, people may say, “Why God created satanic forces?”
現在，人們可能會問：“為什麼上帝創造了邪惡的力量？”
He did not, but eventually they turned out to be because at the second stage, when some
上帝並沒有創造它們，但最終它們卻演變成了邪惡的力量，這是因為在第二階段，
of the Devas, who were created.
有些天神被創造出來。
Again, they were not evolved people, they were created, Devas, in charge of all these
這些天神並非進化而來的人類，而是被創造出來的，
elements and all the working, you see, you have to create also officers or people who
他們掌管著所有這些元素和運作。要知道，你也需要創造一些官員
have to go in the field and work out.
或人員去現場並執行任務。
All these Devas and Devatas: out of their working, what happened [is] that they got
所有這些天神和神祇：由於他們的運作，其中一些迷失了方向，
lost, some of them, and became satanic forces.
變成了惡魔勢力。
Sort of a waste-product came in, and with that waste-product, satanic forces started
某種廢棄物混入其中，惡魔勢力由此滋生，
and they acted in such a way that there was a war during the Kurma-Avatara between Rakshasas
並在龜降世（Kurma-Avatara）期間引發了羅剎
and the Suras, as they call it.
與天神之間的戰爭。
So, the good people who were in charge of the elements, all the working in the office
所以，那些負責元素的善良之人，所有在神職部門工作的人們，
of God started fighting with the satanic forces.
開始與邪惡勢力作戰。
At that time, He Himself worked out this and you know what happened in the amrut-mantan
那時，祂親自參透了這一切，你們也知道在甘露洗禮（amrut-mantan）中發生了什麼
which took place, and this is, – people don’t understand how can the amrut-mantan
——人們不明白甘露洗禮
take place in the bhavasagara, – it did not.
怎麼可能在幻海發生——它並沒有發生。
It took place at a stage which is not bhavasagara.
它發生在幻海之外的階段。
At the bhavasagara it did not take place.
在幻海中界，它並沒有發生。
Now, we are at the bhavasagara state.
現在，我們處於幻海狀態。
At the bhavasagara state the same Kurma, the same one took birth and came on this Earth
在幻海狀態下，同一個龜，同樣的那一位神靈，降生於世，來到這片土地，
and gave us a understanding how to become a proper reptile.
並教導我們如何成為真正的爬蟲類。
Like that we grew up.
就這樣我們進化了。
So, the whole thing will take too much time, I need not go into that.
所以，整個過程太耗時，我就不贅述了。
But, ultimately, a human being was created.
但歸根結底，人類被創造出來。
All this is done by Mahalakshmi power, which has acted through Vishnu, which I have told
這一切都是摩訶拉希什米的力量完成的，她透過毘濕奴神施展神力。我已經告訴你們進化是如何發生的，
you how evolution has taken place, how you are made.
你如何進化，如何被創造出來的。
Now, what is going to happen?
那麼，接下來會發生什麼事呢？
You reach this point, up to this point, till Christ came in.
人類一路走到今天，直到基督降臨。
Christ was also an incarnation and his Mother was nobody else but Radhaji Herself, the Mahalakshmi.
基督也是降世神祈，而他的母親即是羅陀，摩訶拉希什米女神。
And they brought forth up to this stage the human beings.
他們共同孕育了人類，直至今日。
After this, now, what man has to become?
在這之後，人類應該成為什麼樣子？
– is to enter into a state where he becomes nirvichar, means there is no more the consciousness
––– 是進入一種無思慮狀態，在這種狀態下他變得無念，這意味著意識不再存在幻海
of the bhavasagara, but you go little beyond it.
你會超越它。
From this stage you dive into a state of Universal Unconscious, as they call it, it’s nothing
從這個階段開始，你將進入一種他們所謂的「宇宙無意識」狀態，
but the same power which exists here, which is a synthesis of all the three powers, is
它與這裡存在的力量完全相同，
the synthesis of all the three powers.
是三種力量的綜合體。
That is the Adi Shakti’s power.
這就是太初之母的力量。
Adi Shakti’s power is all-pervading, exists everywhere, but we never feel it otherwise.
太初之母的力量無所不在，存在於每個地方，但我們卻從未感受到它。
Why?
為什麼呢？
Because we are very grossly placed.
因為我們的存在非常表面。
We can say, that a tube, which has got, say four layers, out of which it can only use
我們可以說，一根有四層的管子，我們只能使用最外層的管子，
the outer tube, because the inner tubes are all closed.
因為內層的管子都是封閉的。
When the innermost tube is opened out, you become absolutely Self-realised, but when
當最內層的管子打開時，你會得到完全的自覺，
even the second tube is opened out, you can feel the all-pervading force of God Almighty,
即使只打開第二層管子，你也能感受到全能上帝無所不在的力量，
which is, we call it as Sampovapi achetan.
我們稱之為集體無意識。
But it is no more achetan (unconscious) for you because you are conscious of it.
但對你來說，它不再是無意識，因為你已經意識到了它的存在。
That is how you start your dialogue with God.
這就是你開始與上帝對話的開始。
What happens is that here, the reflection here, the reflector, that is reflecting work,
在這裡，反射面，反射器正在反射工作，
from here you ascend into this part.
從這裡你升進到這個部分。
You ascend onto this part.
你升進到這個部分。
You do not become this but you ascend into this area.
你並不是成為這個，而是升進到這個區域。
From here you ascend into this area.
從這裡你登上這個區域。
And this area is filled with the all-pervading power of Adi Shakti.
而這個區域，充滿了太初之母的無所不在的力量。
Till you reach to this stage, you have to go up to this stage of an incarnation, which,
在達到這個境界之前，你必須經歷一次輪迴轉世，
of course, is a big gap.
這當然是一個巨大的鴻溝。
But I can say that Mahavira and Buddha, both of them rose to that height.
但我可以說，摩訶維羅和佛陀，他們都達到了那個高度。
But look at their disciples!
但看看他們的弟子們！
For example, Buddha’s disciples, they have decried Shiva, they have decried all the Gods
例如，佛陀的弟子們，他們貶低了全能主，貶低了所有的神明。
and Goddesses, I mean as if they did not know much about it.
和女神，就好像他們對這些神祇一無所知似的。
And the way they have shown in certain statues – that a Goddess is standing on top of a
而他們在某些雕像中所展示的方式——女神站在一個
Shiva and a Parvati and is trying to kill; She is hitting Shri Ganesha and this is something
全能主和帕爾瓦蒂的上面，並試圖殺死；她擊打象神格泥沙，
so non-sensical.
這簡直荒謬至極。
I mean, they completely killed the image of One United Force, acting the whole thing,
他們完全抹滅了「統一力量」的形象，破壞了所有行動都應遵循同一理念、
in One united idea, with One united mind.
同一思想的原則。
Only whenever they had not united, they became Rakshasas and formed the satanic force.
只有在他們失去團結時，他們才會變成羅剎，並形成邪惡勢力。
As I told you it’s a very, very difficult subject and I’ve tried to handle it in English,
正如我之前所說，這是一個非常非常困難的話題，我試著用英語來解釋，
is even worse.
更是不容易。
So, I’ve tried my level best to do it, but still if you have any questions, anything,
所以，我已經盡力了，但如果你有任何問題，任何事情，
you can ask me, some time, you can write to me, we can find it out.
都可以問我，你可以給我寫信，我們可以一起探討。
For tomorrow…Now, this is the only thing is, I wanted to tell you about this, that
明天……現在，這唯一的事情是，我只想告訴你們一件事，
now you have got thoughtless awareness, no doubt.
毫無疑問，你們現在已經擁有"無思慮"覺知了。
Most of you have got thoughtless awareness, you have got vibrations, but you have to jump
你們大多數人擁有無思慮的覺知，你們有生命能量，但你們必須躍入
into Nirvikalpa.
無疑慮。
And [to] that you have to jump through deep meditation and through deep exposure.
達到無疑慮，你們必須透過深度冥想和深度覺知。
Otherwise, you see, it is no use only having this little state of Nirvichara, you have
否則，你看，僅僅擁有這一點無思慮的狀態是沒有用的，你必須
to jump into Nirvikalpa.
躍入無疑慮。
That is a stage, little, as I’ve told you here, that a little ahead of this reflector,
正如我剛才所說，你們正處於一個階段，一個很小的階段，
you have moved.
你們已經稍微超越了這個反射鏡。
But still you are going up and down, so many of you.
但你們中仍然許多人在上下起伏。
This is a state known as satori in the Zen system of religion, they call it as satori:
這在禪宗的宗教體系中被稱為「悟」，他們稱之為悟：
where, you see, if a person is going up and down, is catching, doing this, that.
你看，如果一個人心緒起伏，忙於各種事情，
This stage has to be overcome.
這種狀態必須克服。
Then you go to the Nirvikalpa state.
然後才能進入無疑慮的狀態。
At the end of the Nirvikalpa state you just don’t catch much.
在無疑慮的狀態的末期，你幾乎不再受感染，
You are not bothered.
你不再為任何事感到困擾。
So far, I haven’t met any human being like that.
到目前為止，我還沒遇過這樣的人。
You see, I have seen very great saints and realised people and I can say that they are
你看，我見過非常偉大的聖人和覺悟的人，我可以肯定地說，
definitely Self-realised, they are even controlling nature, some of them do, but still they catch
他們絕對已經證悟，他們甚至能夠掌控自然，有些人確實如此，但他們仍然會
on their chakras, is something surprising.
受到脈穴感染的影響，這很令人驚訝。
But, you see, human beings are like that, they’ll go on catching and again, perhaps,
但是，你看，人類就是這樣，他們會不斷地受到輪穴感染，或許又會，
they jump into the third state of Self-realisation completely, but they are again in a satori
他們會完全進入自覺的第三階段，但他們又會回到頓悟的狀態，
state and they come back and go back and, like that, may be.
然後又回到原點，如此反覆。
But I have seen that, so far, I have not met one human being whom I will say he is fully
但我看到，到目前為止，我還沒有遇到一個完全
Self-realised, who doesn’t catch.
自覺的人，輪穴不會感染。
Except for me, I find, everybody is catching.
除了我自己，我發現大家輪穴都在感染。
It’s most surprising.
這真是太令人驚訝了。
But when you don’t catch – what happens, when you don’t catch?
但如果你不感染——如果你不會感染，會發生什麼事？
Actually, this is a state rather difficult to achieve.
實際上，這是一種很難達到的狀態。
But if you don’t catch, if you think you don’t catch – how you should do it ?- is
但是如果你不感染，如果你認為你不會感染——你應該怎麼做？
to see this way: that if, supposing, you are catching Agya, maybe.
可以這樣想：假設你的額輪感染，也許。
You must know that when you are catching your Agya, you should not think you are catching
你必須明白，當你的額輪感染，你不應該認為你的額輪感染了
your Agya, but you should think that you are gathering a force here to combat the another
而應該想著自己正在積蓄力量來
person.
對抗對方。
If you can do like that.
如果你能做到這一點
Supposing you are catching on the Vishuddhi chakra, instead of thinking that you are catching
假設你的喉輪感染，與其想著你的喉輪受感染
on Vishuddhi chakra and getting upset about it, if you start thinking that this is a force
並為此感到沮喪，不如開始想著這是你正在積蓄的力量，
you are accumulating just to counterbalance his Vishuddhi chakra.
只是為了平衡對方的喉輪。
Then, I think, it will work out better.
那麼，我認為，情況會好得多。
That’s why I always say that: extend your hands to others and see for yourself.
這就是為什麼我總是說：向他人伸出援手，親身體驗一下。
This has helped many people because if they catch on Agya and if they give vibrations
這幫助了許多人，因為如果他們額輪受到感染，並且如果他們給某個額輪感染的人生命能量
to somebody who is Agya caught, they find they are released.
他們就會發現自己得到了解脫。
Such things are happening to very few but it’s happening.
這種情況雖然只發生在極少數人身上，但確實存在。
So, this is what you can try: that don’t think you are catching but you should think:
所以，這是你可以試試看：不要想著自己正在感染，而是要想：
a force has been accumulated to expel the Agya of another person who is facing you.
一股力量正在積聚，用來驅逐與你對峙之人的額輪。
In the beginning, of course, it’s a very, very slow process, but gradually you can do
當然，一開始這是一個非常非常緩慢的過程，但逐漸地，你就能做到，
it and only people who start giving others.
而且只有那些開始給予他人這種能量的人才能做到。
This is a collective thinking, is a collective thinking: that, supposing, now you can say
這是一種集體思維，是一種集體思維：假設，我感染了瘧疾，
like that, that if, supposing, there is a malaria attack on Me, then My own blood, My
那麼我自己的血液，我自己的血球
own blood cells are trying to combat it.
正在努力抵抗它。
And they are combating it.
而且他們正在對抗它。
You see, if I give in, if I give in, then I become malarious.
你看，如果我屈服，如果我屈服，那麼我就會感染瘧疾。
But if I do not give in, I become victorious.
但如果我不屈服，我就會戰勝它。
In the same way, if you could think this way while giving vibrations: that if you catch
同樣地，如果你在傳遞生命能量時能這樣想：如果你接收到生命能量
it is actually a force being accumulated into you and then you have to give it, then you
它實際上是一股力量在你體內積聚，然後你必須把它傳遞出去，
are going to be much faster than all the munis put together, I can tell you.
那麼我可以告訴你，你的速度會比所有僧侶加起來都快得多。
But that thinking is rather difficult for human beings, because once they catch, they
但這種想法對人類來說相當困難，因為一旦他們受感染，
get little worried, “I’m catching,” they start taking out their own.
就會有些焦慮，“我在感染”，然後他們就開始想辦法去除自己的感染。
If you don’t take out your own and go all out to give it to others, it will work out
如果你不去除自己的感染，並全力以赴地給予他人，效果會更好。
better.
更好。
And this I’ve been, I’ve experimented with one or two people, I’m saying, and
我一直在這樣做，我用一兩個人做過實驗，
it has worked.
而且確實有效。
Everybody does not have that capacity.
不是每個人都具備這種能力。
So, gradually you rise, because you are just now newly born children, you have still to
所以，你要循序漸進地提升，因為你們現在就像新生兒一樣，你們還需要成長，
grow, you have to grow more.
還需要進一步成長。
You might be learned, you might be knowing a lot, that doesn’t mean, as far as your
你可能學識淵博，可能懂得很多，但這並不意味著，
spirituality is concerned, you have just have come out of your satori state, some of you,
就你們的靈性而言，你們有些人，只是剛剛走出頓悟狀態，
and some of you are still in the satori state.
而另一些人仍然處於悟境狀態。
So, be careful about it.
所以，要小心。
I would like to meet you again, perhaps, after two years, I don’t know when.
我希望能在兩年後再次見到你，但我不知道具體是什麼時候。
Tomorrow we are having a meditation here, then I won’t speak much.
明天我們在這裡進行冥想，到時候我不會說太多話。
Tomorrow we have a meditation.
明天我們要進行冥想。
We have a meditation centre here, where you should go and meet, when you meet in a group
我們這裡有一個冥想中心，你們應該去那裡參加。當你們集體參加的時候，
then it is a samuhik, is a group activity, I will be there.
那就是集體活動，我也會在那裡。
You’ll be surprised that my vibrations cannot be felt anywhere so much as they can be felt
你們會驚訝地發現，我的生命能量在其他地方很難感受到，
in a group, about which I know that such and such group is working here.
但在集體活動中卻能感受到。我知道這裡正在進行一個特定的冥想小組。
So, we have already three groups which are working in Delhi.
所以，我們已經有三個小組在德里工作。
And they are made quite closer to the places.
而且他們離目的地很近。
After all, we must know that we don’t have to go to Himalayas, as people went down, we
我們必須明白，我們不必像其他人一樣去喜馬拉雅山，
don’t have to do all these things.
不必經歷這些事情。。
Only thing we have to go is to a place which is very much closer to us, it has been brought
我們唯一需要去的地方，其實離我們很近，它已經來到
to our doors.
我們家門口了。
The whole thing has been brought to your doors: the knowledge, the vibrations, the realisation
所有的一切都來到了你家門口：知識、生命能量、自覺，
and everything is made so easy.
一切都變得如此簡單。
It’s made easy….
它變得如此簡單……
But it should not mean that we should take it for granted.
但這並不意味著我們應該視之為理所當然。
It has been made easy through a very, very great tapasya on my part, I should say.
我應該說，這要歸功於我非常非常艱苦的苦行。
In many ages I’ve been living now for thousands of years and I’ve been working it out on
我已經活了數千年，在無數的時代裡，我研究過
so many human beings and so many things and, at long last, I’ve been able to find out
無數的人和事物，最終，我終於能夠找出
most of the permutations and combinations of most of the human beings and that’s how
絕大多數人的各種排列組合，
it has been worked out in such a large mass-scale.
這就是自覺得以大規模運作的原因。
It would not have been possible if I had not worked it out in that way.
如果我沒有用這種方式研究，這一切都不可能實現。
And that’s how if it has worked out it has to click with most of the people except for
正因如此，它才能適用於大多數人，
one type is very, very difficult, I must say, those who are bound to people who are rakshasas.
但有一種人卻非常非常難，那就是那些與惡魔有牽連的人。
If they are born rakshasas and if your head has touched their feet, it’s a very difficult
如果他們生來就是惡魔，而你的頭碰到了他們的腳，那將是一件非常
thing.
危險的事。
So, I would warn you, that before you touch feet of anybody, you’d be careful about
所以，我要警告你，在你觸碰任何人的腳之前，一定要
it.
小心謹慎。
May God bless you all!
願上帝保佑你們所有人！
It’s already very late for all of you and such a difficult subject to be brought to
對你們所有人來說，時間已經很晚了，要在這麼短的時間內講完這麼複雜的主題，。
such a short time, it’s very difficult.
確實很困難。
I hope to write some book on Sahaja Yoga: ‘I hope’, I am saying, because, so far,
我希望能寫一本關於霎哈嘉瑜伽的書：我說“希望”，是因為到目前為止，
I’ve never written any book.
我還沒有寫過任何書。
[I’m] trying to write some book, but before that some other people are writing.
我正在嘗試寫一本書，但在此之前，其他人已經在寫了。
I hope, I may be able to write something.
我希望，也許我也能寫點什麼。
In any case, you try not to bother too much about these things.
In any case, you try not to bother too much about these things.
This is not so important as your own realisation and your own ascent [because] the whole knowledge
這遠不如你們的自覺和升進重要，因為所有的知識
will be dawned upon you.
都會自然而然地顯現給你們。
You don’t have to bother!
你們不必為此煩惱！
Every word now you read, you will have a meaning about it and you will understand.
現在你們讀到的每一個字，你們都會明白它的意義。
The first thing is that you must get your realisation, second thing is you must ascend.
首先，你必須獲得你的自覺，其次你必須提升自己。
You must ascend much more and give more time to this.
你必須不斷提升，投入更多時間。
Do not take it for granted.
不要把這當作理所當然。
It is a very important thing which you should do.
這是你必須做的非常重要的事情。
After all there are other things, they are important.
當然，還有其他事情，它們也很重要。
But this is the most important thing which has to be done.
但這才是最重要的，你必須去做。
By God’s grace, if it works out I’ll be very happy.
如果一切順利，蒙神恩典，我會很高興。
As it is, I’m extremely happy because in none of my lives I’ve been able to give
即便如此，我已經非常開心了，因為在我的所有人生中，我從未有機會
realisations to so many people.
給予這麼多人自覺。
So as it is, I am over-satisfied with Myself.
所以，我對自己非常滿意。
But as far as you are concerned, you should not be satisfied, you should ask for more
但至於你，你不該滿足，你應該不斷追求更多，
and more and more and it will be granted.
更多，還有更多，而你的願望終將實現。
Because you are the people who are on the stage, you are created for this purpose.
因為你們是站在舞台上的人，你們是為了這個目的而被創造的。
One has to do it.
必須這樣做。
God has to do it.
上帝必須這樣做。
If He does not do it, He cannot fulfil His own desires.
如果祂不這樣做，祂就無法實現祂自己的願望。
And His Creation, He is not going to destroy.
而他的創造，他是不會摧毀的。
May God bless you!
願上帝保佑你！